The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: OK so any pointed questions
教授：好的，所以任何有针对性的问题
before we go over blackjack?
在我们经过二十一点之前？
AUDIENCE: Before you start blackjack
观众：开始二十一点之前
can you go through the rules again?
您可以再次通过规则吗？
PROFESSOR: The rules of the game?
教授：游戏规则？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Well I'm going to do something better
好吧，我会做得更好
than going through the rules.
而不是遵守规则。
I'm going to abstract the rules away.
我将把规则抽象化。
So I'm going to say that a game of blackjack has,
所以我要说的是二十一点游戏
let's start here.
让我们从这里开始。
So a game of blackjack has a deck.
因此，二十一点游戏有一个套牌。
And we have x-ray vision or some other illegal way
我们有X射线视力或其他非法方法
in which we know what the deck looks like from the beginning.
从一开始我们就知道甲板的外观。
How many cards in a deck?
一副牌中有几张牌？
AUDIENCE: 52.
听众：52。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So say from 0 to 51 because we like zero-based indexing.
所以说从0到51，因为我们喜欢从零开始的索引。
So the way that the game starts is you get two cards,
所以游戏开始的方式是得到两张牌，
the dealer gets two cards.
庄家得到两张牌。
What is the only decision that you make in the game
您在游戏中做出的唯一决定是什么
if you already have perfect information?
如果您已经拥有完善的信息？
So you know the deck already.
所以您已经知道套牌了。
You don't need to wait for each card
您无需等待每张卡
to know what it's going to be.
知道会发生什么。
So as the game starts you have to make one decision.
因此，在游戏开始时，您必须做出一个决定。
What's that decision?
那是什么决定？
AUDIENCE: Hit or stand.
听众：击中或站立。
PROFESSOR: Well that's assuming you
教授：那是假设你
care what you get each time.
关心每次得到的东西。
So if you have to look at the card
因此，如果您必须看一下卡片
then you have to decide each time if you hit or stand.
那么您必须决定每次击打还是站立。
If you know all the cards in advance--
如果您事先知道所有卡片，
AUDIENCE: How much to bet?
听众：下注多少？
PROFESSOR: I think our game has that fixed.
教授：我认为我们的游戏已经解决了。
AUDIENCE: When to restart?
听众：什么时候重启？
PROFESSOR: So it is hit or stand,
教授：所以它被击中或站立，
but I want to restate that.
但我想重申一下。
Because you don't actually have to decide after every card
因为您实际上不必在每张卡之后都做出决定
if you want to hit or stand.
如果您想击打或站立。
You know what the cards are going to be in advance.
您知道卡会是什么。
AUDIENCE: When to restart?
听众：什么时候重启？
Like how many cards to pick?
喜欢挑几张卡片？
PROFESSOR: How many cards to pick.
教授：可以挑几张牌。
Yeah that's pretty much the same thing.
是的，几乎是同一回事。
So you don't have to decide every time hit or stand,
因此，您不必每次决定击球或站立时，
you know ahead of time I want to hit three times,
你知道我想提前打三遍，
or I want to hit once.
或者我想打一次。
Because you know the entire deck.
因为你知道整个甲板。
You don't need to actually look at the cards.
您不需要实际看卡片。
So each game the only decision that I make is--
因此，每个游戏我唯一要做的决定是-
suppose this is one game-- the only decision
假设这是一场比赛-唯一的决定
that I have is h, how many cards I'm going to hit.
我有h，我要打几张牌。
Right?
对？
And then after I make this decision
然后我做出这个决定之后
the game will eat up some cards.
游戏会吃掉一些纸牌。
I get two cards, the dealer gets two cards,
我得到两张卡，发牌者得到两张卡，
then I hit some cards then the dealer gets some cards.
然后我打了一些卡，然后发牌者得到了一些卡。
And this is the number of cards that have been consumed.
这是已消耗的卡数。
Some number of cards that were played in this game.
在此游戏中玩过的一些卡牌。
And the other thing that comes out of it
还有另一件事
is how much money I make.
我赚多少钱
For our simple rules it's either I make $1, or nothing,
对于我们的简单规则，要么我赚1美元，要么什么都不赚，
or I lose $1.
否则我损失$ 1。
Fair enough?
很公平？
Everyone follows?
每个人都跟着吗？
So I'm going to abstract all this in a helper method.
因此，我将在一个辅助方法中抽象所有这些内容。
I'm going to say that I have a method called round outcome.
我要说的是，我有一种称为舍入结果的方法。
Where I say, look out of the entire deck
我说的是，从整个甲板望出去
I'm going to start at card i, so this is where my round starts.
我将从卡片i开始，所以这是我的回合开始的地方。
So I tell it which cards I start at.
所以我告诉我从哪张牌开始。
And how many cards I'm going to hit.
以及我要打多少张牌。
And it gives me back a tuple, where the first item
它给了我一个元组，第一个项目
is how many cards are played.
是打多少张牌。
So number of cards played.
所以打的牌数。
And the second item in the tuple is how much money do I make.
元组中的第二项是我赚多少钱。
h is how many cards I'm going to hit.
h是我要打多少张牌。
So i says that I already played this many cards
所以我说我已经打了这么多卡
in previous games.
在以前的游戏中。
So a game starts with a full deck.
因此，游戏始于完整的套牌。
And then I play some rounds.
然后我玩一些回合。
Each round I do a whole exchange with the dealer, where
每回合我都会与经销商进行一次整体交换
I hit some cards, and then the dealer hits some cards.
我打了一些卡，然后发牌者打了一些卡。
And then I win or lose some money.
然后我赢了或赔了一些钱。
AUDIENCE: I don't understand why h and cp are different.
听众：我不明白为什么h和cp不同。
PROFESSOR: So cp is how many cards are played in total.
教授：cp是总共打多少张牌。
And this looks at the initial cards.
这看了最初的牌。
So first I get two cards, the dealer gets two cards.
所以首先我得到两张卡，发牌者得到两张卡。
And then after I hit some cards the dealer also has to hit.
然后，在我打了一些牌之后，发牌者也必须命中。
And the dealer has a pretty find algorithm, right?
经销商有一个漂亮的查找算法，对吗？
So the number of cards played includes
所以打的牌数包括
the cards that were dealt initially
最初发行的卡
and the cars that the dealer has to hit.
以及经销商必须命中的汽车。
So this little thing has all the blackjack rules encoded in it.
因此，这个小东西已在其中编码了所有的二十一点规则。
Everything is already there.
一切都已经在那里。
AUDIENCE: So blackjack, that's roughly 2h?
听众：二十一点，大约是2小时？
cp is 2h, something like that?
cp是2h，诸如此类？
PROFESSOR: 4 plus 2h maybe.
教授：也许是4加2小时。
Because you get two cards, he gets two cards,
因为你得到两张卡，他得到了两张卡，
and if you both deal h on average then--
如果你们俩平均交易h，
AUDIENCE: So is cp the number of cards this round?
观众：cp这回合的张数是多少？
PROFESSOR: This round, yeah.
教授：这回合，是的。
OK so intuitively I already know,
好吧，直觉上我已经知道了
so I already know the entire deck.
所以我已经知道整个甲板了
So the decision that I have to make is,
所以我要做的决定是
would I play optimally every round?
我会在每个回合中发挥最佳吗？
Or do I want to maybe lose the first round
还是我可能会输掉第一轮比赛
and leave some good cards for later?
并留下一些好的卡片供以后使用？
So I have to figure out how many cards I'm
所以我必须弄清楚我有多少张牌
going to hit each time so that overall I make the most
每次都会击中，所以总体上我会发挥最大作用
amount of money when I leave the table.
我离开桌子时的钱数。
And when I run out of cards I leave the table.
当我用完纸牌时，我离开了桌子。
The dealer says shows over, gotta go.
经销商说结束了，得走了。
Do the rules make sense?
规则有意义吗？
OK so I propose we approach this in two ways.
好的，所以我建议我们以两种方式解决这个问题。
First we model it as a graph problem,
首先，我们将其建模为图问题，
because we've already done this a few times.
因为我们已经做过几次了。
And then we model it as a dynamic programming problem.
然后我们将其建模为动态编程问题。
And we see how the two are related.
我们看到两者之间的关系。
Make sense?
说得通？
Is this too simple for everyone?
这对每个人来说都太简单了吗？
You guys already get everything?
你们已经拥有一切了吗？
So how would I model this is a graph problem?
那么我将如何建模这是一个图形问题？
AUDIENCE: Do you already know the order
听众：你已经知道订单了吗
that you're going to get all these cards in?
您将要获得所有这些卡？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: So I in lecture we briefly
听众：所以我在演讲中简要介绍了
talked about having your starting node go
谈到要让您的出发节点走
to a bunch of other nodes that would
到一堆其他节点
be your potential next move, and then
是您潜在的下一步行动，然后
you just calculate your shortest path distance
您只需计算出最短路径距离
from there to the x value.
从那里到x值。
PROFESSOR: So that's the general approach.
教授：那是一般的方法。
How do we do this for cards?
我们该如何为卡进行此操作？
So what would be nodes?
那么节点是什么？
What are the most intuitive nodes you could think about?
您能想到的最直观的节点是什么？
OK maybe intuitive for me.
好吧，也许对我来说很直观。
So nodes show our state, right?
节点显示我们的状态，对吗？
Show the state that the game is currently in.
显示游戏当前的状态。
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: Your hand.
听众：你的手。
Like your current cards.
就像您当前使用的卡片一样。
Is that your state?
那是你的状态吗？
So from I guess 2 to ace.
所以从我猜2到A。
PROFESSOR: From?
教授：来自？
AUDIENCE: From 2 to ace, in terms of the number of choices
听众：从2到ace，就选择数量而言
you have.
你有。
PROFESSOR: OK so the problem is you
教授：好的，问题是你
have four cards of each type, right?
每种类型都有四张卡，对吗？
And you don't know where they show up and everything.
而且您不知道它们出现在哪里以及所有内容。
So I think this my code more complicated than it
所以我认为这比我的代码更复杂
needs to be.
需要是。
AUDIENCE: Like the rest of the cards in the deck
观众：就像卡组中的其他卡片一样
that are remaining?
剩下的？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Is that a good [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：这是一个很好的[听不清]吗？
PROFESSOR: How many cars I have left in the deck, right?
教授：我在甲板上还剩下几辆车，对吗？
So basically I would have one node for each of the cards
所以基本上我将为每个卡有一个节点
here.
这里。
And that says I start a new game at this card.
那就是说我用这张卡开始了一个新游戏。
OK so I'm going to draw some circles.
好，所以我要画一些圆圈。
Say these are our nodes.
说这些是我们的节点。
Maybe I draw a bit too many of them.
也许我画了太多。
Where do we always start?
我们总是从哪里开始？
AUDIENCE: The left side.
听众：左侧。
PROFESSOR: First one, right?
教授：第一个，对吗？
We start with 52 cards.
我们从52张牌开始。
So circle 0 means that we played 0 cards, we have 52 cards left.
所以圈0表示我们打了0张牌，剩下52张牌。
When do we draw an edge between nodes?
我们何时在节点之间绘制边缘？
What does an edge mean?
边缘是什么意思？
AUDIENCE: That's how many cards you've chosen,
听众：您选择了多少张卡，
so the number cp.
所以数字cp。
PROFESSOR: OK so the number cp.
教授：好的，请输入cp。
It means I played a game, right?
这意味着我玩了游戏，对吧？
So one edge is a game.
因此，优势在于游戏。
And it goes from one state to the next state.
它从一个状态转到下一个状态。
So if I'm, say I'm at node i.
因此，如果我在说，我在节点i。
How do I draw the edges?
如何绘制边缘？
Say I'm somewhere here.
说我在这里某处。
So I already played i cards.
所以我已经玩过纸牌了。
AUDIENCE: Iterate through all h's, cp's.
听众：遍历所有h，cp。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So for h in what to what?
那么对于h在什么方面呢？
What's the smallest h?
最小的h是多少？
AUDIENCE: The smallest h is 1.
听众：最小的h为1。
PROFESSOR: Really?
教授：是吗？
Do I have to hit?
我必须打吗？
AUDIENCE: Wait isn't it 4?
听众：等等，不是4吗？
Because you're always dealing out 4.
因为你总是在处理4。
PROFESSOR: Yes, so I might as well not count them, right?
教授：是的，所以我最好不要数一下，对吗？
So h is how many cards I hit after the initial ones were
所以h是我最初打几张牌后
dealt.
处理。
So that I can start at 0, a nice and easy number.
这样我就可以从0开始，这是一个很好的数字。
And where do I end?
我在哪里结束？
Rough approximation.
粗略近似。
AUDIENCE: You could go to infinity and then break.
听众：你可以去无穷远然后打破。
It's still 11 because 11 at most-- oh no, 11 minus 4, 6.
它仍然是11，因为最多是11 –哦，不，11减去4、6。
You need to know the rules of the game.
您需要了解游戏规则。
PROFESSOR: OK if you know the rules of the game it's that.
教授：好的，如果您知道游戏规则就是这样。
If you don't know the rules of the game it's 52 minus i.
如果您不知道游戏规则，那就是52减去i。
OK so what's first thing I do?
好，那我第一件事是什么？
So how do I draw an edge representing
那我怎么画一个代表
a game where I hold h cards?
我持有h卡的游戏？
AUDIENCE: So you draw an edge from your current place
听众：因此，您可以从当前位置吸引边缘
to the output of round outcome with the 0 element.
到带有0元素的舍入结果的输出。
PROFESSOR: So then let's store this output somewhere.
教授：那么让我们将输出存储在某个地方。
Let's say o is round outcome.
假设o是舍入结果。
What do I give round outcome?
我应该给出什么结果？
AUDIENCE: i and h.
听众：我和h。
PROFESSOR: See I picked good names.
教授：看我选了好名字。
They're exactly what I have there.
它们正是我在那里的东西。
So I draw an edge from i to what?
所以我从我到什么都占了优势？
AUDIENCE: To the output of round outcome, which is o.
听众：对于舍入结果的输出，即o。
So it's 0.
所以是0
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: Or that the node at o is 0.
听众：或o处的节点为0。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So suppose I'm at i and I've already played
所以，假设我在我身边，我已经玩过
five cards, right?
五张卡，对不对？
So say i equals 5, for example.
举例来说，假设我等于5。
And I know that if I hit once the dealer will also
而且我知道，如果我打了一次，庄家也会
have to hit once.
必须打一次。
So in total I've played 6 cards.
因此，我总共打了6张牌。
And suppose I won.
假设我赢了。
Then the output would look like this.
然后输出看起来像这样。
6 cards were played and I won.
玩了6张牌，我赢了。
So plus 1.
所以加1。
So I would draw an edge from 5 to what?
所以我会从5到什么画一条边缘？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, from 5 to 11 hopefully.
教授：好的，希望是5到11。
So what's 11?
那11是什么？
11 is 5 plus all of 0.
11是5加上所有0。
OK, what am I missing there?
好，我在那里想念什么？
AUDIENCE: i to i plus [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我到我加[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So this tells me how many cards I played in this game.
因此，这告诉我在此游戏中玩了多少张牌。
I want to look at each game separately.
我想分别看每个游戏。
I don't want to have to keep track of previous states.
我不想跟踪以前的状态。
So this output is localized to this game.
因此，此输出被本地化为该游戏。
It tells me how many cards have been
告诉我已经有多少张卡了
drawn in this game in total.
总共在这个游戏中被抽中。
And how much money I made in this game.
以及我在这个游戏中赚了多少钱。
If I already played i cards before starting the game,
如果我在开始游戏之前已经玩过纸牌，
after I play all of 0, the total number of cards is i plus 0.
当我全部打完0后，纸牌总数为i加0。
Tiny detail, but you'd probably lose a point off
微小的细节，但您可能会损失一点
of an exam or something if you forget it.
考试或忘记的东西。
OK so keep track of your state.
确定，因此请跟踪您的状态。
It makes sense to write down this is my state,
写下这是我的状态很有意义，
and then make sure that you're always representing it.
然后确保您始终代表它。
So what's the cost of the edge?
那么边缘的成本是多少？
And then our answer would be what path do I want?
然后我们的答案将是我要走什么路？
I want to make the most amount of money,
我想赚很多钱
so that's the longest path.
所以这是最长的道路。
How do I convert this to a shortest path problem,
如何将其转换为最短路径问题，
because this is what you know how to solve?
因为这是您知道如何解决？
Where I put it?
我放在哪里？
AUDIENCE: There.
听众：在那里。
PROFESSOR: Good answer, there.
教授：好的答案。
Right there.
在那里。
OK so this builds the graph, then
好，这样就可以建立图表了，然后
I run some algorithm on it.
我在上面运行了一些算法。
What's the best algorithm I can run on it?
我可以在其上运行的最佳算法是什么？
AUDIENCE: Dykstra because you can [INAUDIBLE].
听众：Dykstra是因为您可以[听不清]。
But you can add everything on.
但是您可以添加所有内容。
The lowest negative edge weight is 1, or negative 1.
最低负边缘权重为1或负1。
PROFESSOR: Are there negative cycles?
教授：是否存在负周期？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: Everything goes right, right?
教授：一切顺利，对吗？
So even if I don't get hit any card,
因此，即使我没有被击中，
at least four cards will be played.
至少要玩四张牌。
So all these arrows go right.
因此，所有这些箭头都正确。
So then I heard a fancy term that I like.
因此，我听到了一个我喜欢的花哨的名词。
Can someone say it again?
有人可以再说一次吗？
What's this graph?
这是什么图？
AUDIENCE: DAG.
听众：DAG。
PROFESSOR: DAG.
教授：达格。
All the edges go one way.
所有的边缘都是一种方式。
So this is a DAG.
这是DAG。
And that means that I can run what algorithm?
那意味着我可以运行什么算法？
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Topological sort plus DFS,
教授：拓扑排序加DFS，
the one that we talked about last time when everyone was out
上次大家都在谈论的那个
for Thanksgiving.
感恩节
So you have to believe me that it
所以你必须相信我
exists, or look at lecture notes.
存在，或查看讲义。
So top sort plus DFS will give me
所以顶级排序加上DFS将给我
the shortest path in order of V plus E.
V + E的最短路径。
So this is better than Dykstra, which is E plus V log V. OK?
因此，这比Dykstra好，后者是E加V logV。好吗？
OK I'm guessing most of you don't
好吧，我猜你们大多数人都不
know how that algorithm works.
知道该算法如何工作。
Well good news, we're going to do
好消息，我们要做
this using dynamic programming.
这使用动态编程。
So we're going to represent the graph implicitly.
因此，我们将隐式表示图。
And we're going to write everything
而且我们将编写所有内容
without needing to know the algorithm.
无需了解算法。
If you know it, it helps because you can see how they relate.
如果您知道它，它会有所帮助，因为您可以看到它们之间的关系。
But if you don't we should still be able to solve the problem.
但是，如果您不这样做，我们仍然应该能够解决问题。
But before we do that, does everyone understand this?
但是在我们这样做之前，每个人都了解吗？
Some nods would be nice so that I can feel good.
有些点头会很好，这样我才能感觉良好。
Yes?
是？
Almost?
几乎？
OK.
好。
Questions?
有什么问题吗
AUDIENCE: Like the number 5 there,
听众：就像那里的数字5，
that's only if you hit, right?
只有当你击中时，对吗？
Or that's the number of cards remaining.
或那是剩余的卡数。
Is there a particular reason you picked 5?
您选择5个特殊原因吗？
PROFESSOR: So I was choosing an example for i.
教授：所以我正在为我选择一个例子。
So good question, what does i mean?
好问题，我是什么意思？
So this means I'm-- assume that I'm starting a game.
因此，这意味着我假设自己正在开始游戏。
So starting-- sorry, a round.
所以开始-对不起，一回合。
A new round.
新一轮。
And I have already played i cards in the previous round.
而且我已经在上一轮打过i卡了。
So I started a new round and the first 5 cards
所以我开始了新一轮比赛，前五张牌
are out of the deck.
不在甲板上。
What's the best strategy I can have?
我能拥有的最佳策略是什么？
What's the most money I can make?
我能赚到的最大钱是多少？
AUDIENCE: But there's some nodes that
听众：但是有些节点
connect to the next card over that won't necessarily
连接到不需要的下一张卡
end the game, so there aren't going
结束游戏，所以就没有了
to be any earnings, right?
算什么收入吧？
You could have 5 connect to 6, and that wouldn't--
您可以将5个连接到6个，但这不会-
PROFESSOR: Here I'm just trying to emphasize the point
教授：在这里，我只是想强调一点
that all the edges move, all the edges point forward.
所有边缘都移动，所有边缘都指向前方。
But yeah, the edges have to go at least across four nodes.
但是，是的，边缘必须至少跨越四个节点。
So assume there are some more nodes around here.
因此，假设这里还有更多的节点。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: Yes?
教授：是吗？
AUDIENCE: You were saying how you
听众：你说的是你
have to be careful with something
一定要小心点
or else you'll lose a point.
否则你会失去一点。
What was that?
那是什么？
PROFESSOR: How you draw your edges.
教授：如何绘制边缘。
Or when we switch to dynamic programming, what
或者当我们切换到动态编程时，
you write in your recursion.
您在递归中编写。
OK so last chance to ask a question
好的，所以最后一次提出问题的机会
before we do a conceptual jump and use another algorithm.
在进行概念上的跳转之前，请使用另一种算法。
OK how do we do this using the dynamic programming?
好的，我们如何使用动态编程做到这一点？
So what are we going to have instead of nodes?
那么我们将要拥有什么而不​​是节点呢？
Sorry?
抱歉？
Well so you still have states in both cases.
好吧，在这两种情况下，您仍然都有状态。
But here you represent them with nodes in a graph.
但是在这里，您可以在图中用节点表示它们。
In dynamic programming you represent them using-- yeah,
在动态编程中，您使用-代表它们，
the states are basically sub-problems.
状态基本上是子问题。
And what do we, when we compute stuff, what do we use?
当计算东西时，我们使用什么呢？
Numbers is a vector or in a matrix.
数字是向量或矩阵。
So there's no graph to work with.
因此，没有可用的图形。
There are no extra algorithms to call.
没有额外的算法可调用。
We just straight up compute to the numbers,
我们只计算数字
we trade the answers to the problem.
我们用问题的答案来交换。
So we're going to have an array.
因此，我们将有一个数组。
How many elements in the array?
数组中有多少个元素？
Can anyone guess?
谁能猜得到？
All right, I heard 52.
好吧，我听到了52。
If I'm at element i, say i equals 5 because we used that
如果我在元素i上，则说我等于5，因为我们用过
before, what does this represent in the dynamic programming
以前，这在动态编程中代表什么
formulation?
公式？
It's very similar to node 5 there.
这与那里的节点5非常相似。
So what does it represent?
那代表什么呢？
The fact that we're starting a game after we
在我们开始游戏后，
played the first five cards.
打了前五张牌。
Sorry, we're starting a round after we've
抱歉，我们已经开始一轮比赛了
played the first 5 cards.
玩了前5张牌。
And we want to maximize our earnings from here on.
我们希望从现在开始使我们的收益最大化。
So then the problem is, how do we
那么问题是，我们如何
maximize our earnings starting here?
从这里开始最大化我们的收入？
So given that the deck has these cards,
因此，鉴于甲板上有这些卡片，
so the cards from 5 to 51.
所以从5到51
What's the maximum amount of money
最高金额是多少
we can make by playing optimally?
我们可以通过最佳发挥来赚钱吗？
So maximum number of money we can
所以我们可以最大数量的钱
win by playing optimally, starting around at card i.
从最佳状态开始，从第一张牌开始获胜。
Starting at i.
从我开始。
So if I want to compute this-- by the way, speaking
所以，如果我想计算这个，顺便说一句
of bad variable names, we did this before.
错误的变量名，我们之前已经做到了。
When people don't know how to name this array
当人们不知道如何命名该数组时
they name it dpi.
他们将其命名为dpi。
I think we did that in our PSet.
我认为我们在PSet中做到了。
So this is the most useless name you can have for the array.
因此，这是您可以为数组使用的最无用的名称。
It just tells you that we're using dynamic programming.
它只是告诉您我们正在使用动态编程。
But it doesn't really tell you what it means.
但这并不能真正告诉您这是什么意思。
So we're going to go for it, because it's
所以我们要去做，因为它
nice and easy to write.
很容易写。
So if I want to compute dp of i, how do I do that?
因此，如果我想计算i的dp，该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: x [INAUDIBLE] problems.
听众：x [听不清]问题。
PROFESSOR: OK, so what are the sub-problems?
教授：好的，那么子问题是什么？
AUDIENCE: The function at i's past 5
听众：我过去5岁时的功能
where the i's are [INAUDIBLE] through this manner.
通过这种方式，我是[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK so I'd want to have something very similar
教授：好的，我想有一些非常相似的东西
to this, right?
对此吧？
What are my decisions?
我的决定是什么？
So what are my choices?
那我有什么选择呢？
What do I iterate over?
我要遍历什么？
AUDIENCE: How many hits.
听众：点击几下。
PROFESSOR: Yep, exactly the same thing as before, right?
教授：是的，和以前完全一样，对吗？
Starting a node at i.
在i处启动节点。
I was starting a node at i here.
我在这里开始一个节点。
So the choices are exactly the same.
因此，选择是完全相同的。
So I'm going to start by looking at this line.
因此，我将从看这行开始。
Do I need to make any changes?
我需要进行任何更改吗？
Or do I copy straight over?
还是我直接复印？
So this is the algorithm for computing dp of i.
这就是计算i的dp的算法。
For i in 0 to 52.
对于0至52中的i。
Sorry h in 52 minus i.
对不起，h在52减去i。
All right.
好吧。
I hope we can do a bit better than that.
我希望我们可以做得更好。
AUDIENCE: So we know that it's a max of 6, right?
观众：所以我们知道最大为6，对​​吗？
So can we just put that in instead?
那么我们可以把它放进去吗？
That's given the rules.
给出了规则。
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
If you're smart you can.
如果您很聪明，可以。
I'm not, so I'm just writing this.
我不是，所以我只是在写这篇。
So this helper function that I have here,
所以我在这里有这个辅助功能
that I call the magic that implements
我称之为实现的魔法
the rules of bag check will save me.
行李托运的规则可以救我。
So if I say that oh, I want to hit 10 times,
所以如果我说哦，我想打10次，
and that's impossible, then it'll probably give me
那是不可能的，那可能会给我
an earning of minus infinity, which makes sure
负无穷大的收益，这可以确保
I never choose that path.
我从不选择那条路。
So all that is hidden in there.
因此所有隐藏在其中。
You're smart enough in blackjack so you can write 6.
您在二十一点中足够聪明，因此您可以写6。
I'm not so I can't.
我不是，所以我不能。
So 52 minus i.
所以52减去我
OK what I do next?
好，我接下来要做什么？
Do I copy this next line?
我要复制下一行吗？
Or do I change it?
还是我要改变它？
Yeah let's copy it over.
是的，让我们将其复制过来。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
Do I copy this?
我要复制吗？
Trick question.
技巧问题。
Come on guys.
拜托了伙计们。
So do I copy this line or not?
那我是否复制此行？
Do I have a graph here?
我在这里有图吗？
Can I draw edges?
我可以画边吗？
OK so I'm not going to copy it.
好，所以我不会复制它。
What do I do instead?
我该怎么办？
By trick I mean easy.
通过技巧，我的意思是简单。
So what do I do instead?
那我该怎么办呢？
I compute my answer directly.
我直接计算我的答案。
So if I hit h cards, what am I looking at?
所以，如果我打h牌，我在看什么？
AUDIENCE: Do you mean like a function?
听众：您的意思是喜欢一个功能吗？
PROFESSOR: A function, sorry?
教授：一个功能，对不起？
AUDIENCE: You add the dp of o 1 or of o 0.
听众：您添加了o 1或o 0的dp。
PROFESSOR: OK so first let's see if I have i cards,
教授：好的，让我们先看看我是否有i卡，
and say I hit, I do the same exact thing that I did before.
并说我打了，我做了和以前一样的事情。
I look at i is 5 and h equals 2.
我看我是5，h等于2。
So then that function gives me the same answer, 6 1.
所以那个函数给了我相同的答案6 1。
So then I know that after this I'm going to end up in a state
所以我知道在那之后我将最终处于一种状态
where I played the first 11 cards.
我打了前11张牌。
So I'm going to end up at 11.
所以我将以11结尾。
How much money did I make overall?
我总共赚了多少钱？
OK, so 1 in this case.
好的，所以在这种情况下为1。
So how much money I made is o of-- I think it's o of 1.
所以我赚了多少钱-我认为是1。
And after I land here, how much money I'm going to make?
在我到达这里后，我将赚多少钱？
Assuming I'm still playing optimally.
假设我还在发挥最佳状态。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: dp i plus.
教授：dp我加。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
OK.
好。
So i plus o of 0 is used to compute--
所以我加上0的o用于计算-
so dp of i plus o of 0 is used to compute dp of i.
因此，i的dp加上0的o用于计算i的dp。
This is the same thing as--
这与-
AUDIENCE: dp is a function here?
听众：dp是这里的功能吗？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
So you're wondering what the hell?
所以你想知道到底是什么？
Why will that work, right?
为什么会起作用，对吗？
Let's get to that in a minute.
让我们在一分钟内解决这个问题。
That will work, we have to make it work.
那将起作用，我们必须使其起作用。
So here I'm drawing an edge from i to i plus o of 0.
所以在这里我画的是从i到i加上0的o的边。
And the cost of the edge is minus o of 1.
边缘的成本为负o的1。
So here we're looking at edges.
因此，这里我们要看边缘。
Here I'm assuming that they already
在这里，我假设他们已经
computed the answer here using some black magic.
使用一些黑魔法计算了答案。
It's already available.
它已经可用。
And I want to compute the answer here.
我想在这里计算答案。
So I have the cost of the edge plus whatever I had here.
因此，我要付出成本的代价，再加上我在这里所拥有的一切。
So if, suppose I know that if I start here
所以，如果我知道如果我从这里开始
and I finish the deck, I can make $20.
然后我完成了套牌，我可以赚20美元。
So suppose I know that this is 20.
因此，假设我知道这是20。
What will the answer be here?
答案是什么？
1 plus 20 which is?
1加20是什么？
So if I hit-- how many times did I say there-- if I hit twice
所以如果我打了-我说了几次-如果我打了两次
I guess I'll make 21.
我想我会21岁。
So this is a possible answer.
因此，这是一个可能的答案。
And I have to go over all possible answers.
我必须仔细研究所有可能的答案。
So this is how much I'm making if I hit h cards, right?
所以，如果我打h牌，这就是我要赚多少钱，对吗？
Now I'm looking at multiple choices here.
现在，我在这里查看多种选择。
This is the answer for each choice.
这是每个选择的答案。
Which answer do I want in the end?
我到底想要哪个答案？
The largest.
最大的。
OK.
好。
So let's say I'm going to start with a choices array that
因此，假设我将从一个选择数组开始
stores all the answers.
存储所有答案。
So here I'm just going to pend the answer,
所以在这里我只想提出答案，
the possible answer.
可能的答案。
Choices append this guy.
选择附加此人。
And then at the end of the for loop
然后在for循环的结尾
I'm going to take the max of choices,
我将尽最大的选择，
and I'm going to assign it where?
我要把它分配到哪里？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So I promised I'm going to compute dp of i.
教授：所以我保证我要计算i的dp。
I just finished computing dp of i.
我刚完成i的dp计算。
Now there's a little problem here.
现在这里有一个小问题。
In order to compute this guy, I need
为了计算这个家伙，我需要
to already have the answer for this guy.
已经有了这个家伙的答案。
And maybe for some other guys here.
也许对于这里的其他人。
So an answer here depends on future answers.
因此，这里的答案取决于将来的答案。
The arrows here are the same as the arrows here, right?
这里的箭头与这里的箭头相同，对吗？
They represent possible moves in the game.
它们代表游戏中的可能动作。
At the same time the arrows here represent dependencies.
同时，这里的箭头表示依赖关系。
This answer depends on this answer,
这个答案取决于这个答案，
this answer depends on this answer, so on and so forth.
这个答案取决于这个答案，依此类推。
When we hear the word dependencies
当我们听到依赖性一词时
what do we think of?
我们怎么看？
Topological sort.
拓扑排序。
PSet, which one?
PSet，哪一个？
PSet 6 still brings painful memories?
PSet 6仍然带来痛苦的回忆吗？
Not anymore.
不再。
We have a new one.
我们有一个新的。
So in order to compute this I need
所以为了计算这个，我需要
to compute the answer to a few other sub-problems.
计算其他一些子问题的答案。
To make sure that I have these answers ready by the time
为了确保我已经准备好这些答案
I compute this.
我计算一下。
So to make sure that this code doesn't
因此，请确保该代码不会
crash I have to compute all the answers to the sub-problems
崩溃我必须计算所有子问题的答案
in the topological sort order.
按拓扑排序顺序。
That's where topological sort fits in here.
这就是拓扑排序适合的地方。
What's an obvious topological sort,
什么是明显的拓扑排序，
if all the edges are pointing this way?
如果所有的边缘都指向这种方式？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yep, thank you guys.
教授：是的，谢谢。
So start at the easiest problem.
因此，从最简单的问题开始。
What do you do if you have one card?
如果有一张卡怎么办？
And then go look at bigger and bigger and bigger problems,
然后去看越来越大的问题，
until we tackle the hard problems
直到我们解决难题
of what I do with the entire deck.
我整个甲板的工作
So when I compute this problem I'm going to go to iterate how?
所以当我计算这个问题时，我将去迭代该怎么做？
From where to where?
从哪里到哪里？
AUDIENCE: 52 minus i to the 0.
受众群体：52减去0。
You're actually--
你实际上是
PROFESSOR: So this is i.
教授：这就是我。
AUDIENCE: Oh, that's i.
听众：哦，就是我。
PROFESSOR: So where do i go from here?
教授：那我从这里去哪里？
AUDIENCE: 51 to 0.
观众：51比0。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
So now whenever I access this guy
所以现在无论何时我访问这个人
I know it's already computed.
我知道它已经计算了。
So the code isn't going to crash.
因此，代码不会崩溃。
OK and this thing is my topological sort.
好的，这是我的拓扑排序。
So the advantage of this is that the code
所以这样做的好处是代码
is a lot smaller, right?
小很多吧？
Here I'm building the graph.
我在这里建立图表。
So I'm calling some graph methods.
所以我在调用一些图形方法。
And then I would have to have the code for computing
然后我必须要有用于计算的代码
the shortest path in a DAG.
DAG中最短的路径。
And then I would have to have some code for extracting
然后我将需要一些代码来提取
the answer using that.
使用该答案。
Here this is all the code.
这是所有代码。
It's a few lines.
几行。
And it's because the graph is represented implicitly.
这是因为该图是隐式表示的。
The topological sort is represented implicitly.
拓扑排序是隐式表示的。
The edges are represented implicitly.
边缘隐式表示。
So this looks like magic.
因此，这看起来像魔术。
But if you know where to look you'll find the items.
但是，如果您知道在哪里看，就会找到这些物品。
You'll find the things that tell you what the graph looks like.
您会发现告诉您图形外观的内容。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So that tells you how much money
听众：所以这告诉你多少钱
you can make, but does it tell you can--
你可以做，但是它告诉你可以-
PROFESSOR: How you make it?
教授：您是如何做到的？
Not yet.
还没。
Parent pointers.
父指针。
Yeah that's a good point.
是的，这很不错。
Let me see how we're doing on time.
让我看看我们的工作情况如何。
OK.
好。
I can talk parent pointers.
我可以谈父母的指针。
Am I missing anything else?
我还有什么想念的吗？
There's one decision that I'm missing,
我想念一个决定，
that I missed here too.
我也想念这里。
If things look bad for you, if you
如果情况对您不利，如果您
know you're going to lose money, what can you do?
知道您将要亏钱，该怎么办？
Walk away.
走开。
How much do you get?
你得到多少？
AUDIENCE: 0.
听众：0。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So you always have an edge that takes you
所以你总是拥有带你的优势
all the way out with cost 0.
一直到成本为0。
So the way I represent that here is I start with a choice of 0.
所以我在这里表示的方式是从0开始选择。
OK now let's do parent pointers.
好，现在让我们做父指针。
What's the easiest way of doing parent pointers?
做父指针最简单的方法是什么？
AUDIENCE: Keep track of the max of-- [INAUDIBLE].
听众：跟踪-[听不清]的最大值。
PROFESSOR: So I want to keep track-- for every answer here
教授：所以，我想跟踪一下-这里的每个答案
I want to keep back of the h that led me to that answer.
我想回避导致我给出答案的h。
So in the dynamic programming vector,
所以在动态编程向量中
instead of just storing the maximum cost,
而不是仅仅存储最高成本，
I'm going to store the maximum cost and the number of hits
我要存储最高费用和点击次数
I have to make to get there.
我必须去那儿。
So instead of having one number here that's 21
所以这里不是21
I'm going to have two numbers.
我要有两个数字。
I'm going to have 21 and the 1 that
我将要拥有21和1
says you have to hit-- sorry, 2-- you have to hit twice.
说你必须打-对不起，2-你必须打两次。
And then you'll go on this arrow and so on and so forth.
然后，您将继续按此箭头，依此类推。
And if you know how many hits you
如果你知道有多少击中
have to make you can follow this--
必须使您可以遵循此-
you can follow these parent pointers
您可以按照这些父指针
and they will tell you how to play the entire game.
他们会告诉您如何玩整个游戏。
You start at 0 and play the entire game.
您从0开始，然后玩整个游戏。
Do we want to change the pseudocode to do that?
我们是否要更改伪代码来做到这一点？
OK, it's not too hard.
好吧，这不太难。
How many people want to see the pseudocode changes?
有多少人希望看到伪代码更改？
All right, I guess I don't have to write it then.
好吧，我想我不必再写了。
OK any questions on this?
对此有任何疑问吗？
So the change is really simple.
因此，更改非常简单。
Instead of storing one number you store a tuple.
而不是存储一个数字，而是存储一个元组。
And then because tuples are sorted
然后因为元组被排序
the right way maximum still works.
正确的方法仍然可以发挥最大作用。
You don't have to change that, you just
您不必更改它，您只需
have to change what you store down there.
必须更改您在那里存储的内容。
AUDIENCE: So you just add h in, into your--
听众：因此，您只需将h加入，
PROFESSOR: Yeah, you add one more parentheses for the tuple.
教授：是的，您还为元组添加了一个括号。
Wait, I already have two, OK, never mind.
等等，我已经有两个了，好的，没关系。
AUDIENCE: You have to go through your choices, so you just--
听众：您必须进行选择，所以您-
AUDIENCE: Is there any difference in making
听众：制作上有什么区别吗
a separate dictionary for parent pointers?
父指针的单独字典？
Does it make any difference in run time?
它对运行时间有什么影响吗？
PROFESSOR: Absolutely no difference running time.
教授：绝对没有差异。
The code is, it might be more complicated,
代码可能更复杂，
it might be more simple, depending
可能更简单，具体取决于
on how your brain works.
关于你的大脑如何运作。
It's easier to patch existing code
修补现有代码更容易
to add in parent pointers this way.
以这种方式添加父指针。
If you're writing new code it might
如果您正在编写新代码，则可能
be easier for you to have a separate dictionary.
更容易拥有单独的字典。
This is fewer lines of code though.
不过，这是更少的代码行。
OK any questions on this?
对此有任何疑问吗？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Could I generalize and say
听众：我可以概括地说
that if you have a topological sort
如果您具有拓扑排序
you can do everything backwards.
你可以倒退一切。
Otherwise you should use memoization.
否则，您应该使用备忘录。
PROFESSOR: So actually you're doing it
教授：所以实际上您正在这样做
in the order of the topological sort.
按照拓扑排序的顺序。
You're not doing it backwards.
您不是在向后做。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK sorry.
听众：哦，对不起。
If you have a topological sort then
如果您有拓扑排序，那么
you should do it in that order.
您应该按顺序进行。
But if you don't have a topological sort
但是，如果您没有拓扑结构
then you should do memoization.
那你应该做个回忆
PROFESSOR: If you don't know the topological sort.
教授：如果您不知道拓扑排序。
But there has to be one, right?
但是必须有一个，对不对？
Because otherwise you have infinite loops.
因为否则，您将陷入无限循环。
If you have an infinite loop in your dependency graph,
如果您的依存关系图中有无限循环，
then you're not going to have an answer.
那么您将不会有答案。
So that means you're dp formulation is bad.
这意味着您的dp配方不好。
Fortunately for all the problems that we
幸运的是，我们遇到的所有问题
have the topological sort is pretty obvious.
具有拓扑排序是相当明显的。
It either grows from 0 to the problem size or the other way
它要么从0增长到问题的大小，要么相反
around.
周围。
AUDIENCE: So then memoization is?
听众：那么回忆是什么？
PROFESSOR: So memoization is, it's
教授：所以回忆是
more of a proof of concept thing.
更多的是概念证明。
It shows you that if you have the recursion,
它表明，如果您有递归，
everything else can be done automatically.
其他一切都可以自动完成。
So like if you build a graph then you can run top sort
因此，就像您创建图表一样，您可以运行顶级排序
and get the answer, you don't have to think about it.
并获得答案，您无需考虑。
We think about it because the code is smaller
我们考虑一下是因为代码较小
if we do it this way.
如果我们这样做的话。
If I'd have to write memoization I
如果我必须写备忘录，
would add 4 or 5 more lines, right?
会增加4或5行，对吧？
But the point of doing it that way is, all you need
但是这样做的关键是，您需要的一切
is that recursion.
是那个递归。
If you have this-- so this is the magic part.
如果您有这个-这就是神奇的部分。
If you have this, so this line here of what your choices are
如果您有此选择，那么此行就是您的选择
and max, how you combine them, then everything else
最大，如何将它们结合起来，然后再进行其他操作
is mechanical.
是机械的。
Once you've solved enough problems
一旦解决了足够的问题
everything else is just follow the process.
其他一切都只是按照流程进行。
So this is the equivalent of in graph problems,
因此，这等同于图形问题，
the hard part is figuring out what the state is.
困难的部分是弄清楚状态是什么。
Once you know what the state you know
一旦知道状态就知道了
that these are the vertices, and you
这些是顶点，而你
know how to draw edges between them.
知道如何在它们之间绘制边缘。
And then you know what algorithm to run.
然后，您知道要运行哪种算法。
So the hard part is still knowing what the state is.
因此，最困难的部分仍然是了解状态。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
So this is dynamic programming.
所以这是动态编程。
Smaller code.
较小的代码。
This is the graph approach.
这是图形方法。
They essentially compute the same thing.
他们本质上计算的是同一件事。
This is more code, this is less code.
这是更多代码，这是更少代码。
And if you see the correspondence between them
如果您看到他们之间的对应关系
then you understand the problem a little bit better.
那么您对问题的理解会更好一些。
The main point is when you have a new problem
要点是当您遇到新问题时
you can approach it either way.
您可以采用任何一种方式进行处理。
If you see the dynamic programming solution right away
如果您立即看到动态编程解决方案
write it down, you're done.
写下来，就完成了。
If not, draw the graph.
如果没有，请绘制图形。
Think of what the state is, draw the edges.
考虑一下状态是什么，画出边缘。
And then after that you can write the math.
然后，您可以编写数学公式。
OK let's talk about a new problem.
好，让我们谈一个新问题。
Let's talk about the problem that shows up on interviews.
让我们谈谈面试中出现的问题。
People excited about interviews?
人们对采访感到兴奋吗？
OK suppose you have a sequence of numbers,
好吧，假设您有一个数字序列，
I'm going to draw a sequence here.
我要在这里画一个顺序。
And you want to find the shortest
而您想找到最短的
increasing sub-sequence.
增加子序列。
So you get to choose some numbers out of these numbers.
因此，您可以从这些数字中选择一些数字。
And they have to form an increasing sequence.
而且它们必须形成一个递增的序列。
So for example this is a sequence.
例如，这是一个序列。
It happens to be increasing.
它恰好正在增加。
This is also a sequence, but it's not increasing.
这也是一个序列，但没有增加。
So it's not a valid answer.
因此，这不是一个有效的答案。
And I want the longest sequence, the longest sub-sequence
我想要最长的序列，最长的子序列
that is increasing.
越来越多。
Does the problem make sense?
这个问题有意义吗？
How do we solve it?
我们该如何解决？
Do we want to solve it using dynamic programming
我们是否想使用动态编程解决它
or using graphs?
或使用图表？
OK so votes for dynamic programming.
好的，为动态编程投票。
Votes for graph.
投票给图表。
Well too bad, it looks prettier as a graph.
太糟糕了，它看起来更漂亮。
So how do we solve it as a dynamic programming problem?
那么我们如何解决它作为动态编程问题呢？
What are the sub-problems?
有哪些子问题？
AUDIENCE: The largest sub-sequence
观众：最大的子序列
PROFESSOR: Starting somewhere, right?
教授：从某处开始吧？
I'm going to go off that answer because I
我要回答这个问题，因为我
know how to go off of it better.
知道如何更好地解决它。
So say start here.
所以说从这里开始。
Say start at 4.
从4开始说。
Or actually say I start at 3.
或实际上说我从3开始。
I have two choices.
我有两个选择。
5, which is closer to me.
5，离我更近。
And 4.
和4。
Well I have a few more choices, but they're further away.
好吧，我还有其他选择，但是距离还很远。
Whatever.
随你。
So these are my choices starting at 3.
这些是我从3开始的选择。
If I decide that I'm going to go from 3 to 4
如果我决定我将从3变到4
and the next number I choose is 4,
我选择的下一个数字是4，
now I want the longest sub-sequence
现在我想要最长的子序列
starting at 4, right?
从4开始吧？
It still has to be longest sub-sequence.
它仍然必须是最长的子序列。
So from here on, no matter what happened before,
所以从现在开始，无论发生了什么事，
my behavior still has to be optimal.
我的行为仍然必须是最佳的。
If instead I chose 7, I don't care what happened before.
如果我选择了7，那么我不在乎之前发生了什么。
The behavior still has to be optimal.
行为仍然必须是最佳的。
So a sub-problem says start at number i.
因此，一个子问题说从第i个开始。
So starting at number i.
所以从第一号开始。
By the way we're going to use zero-based indexing again
顺便说一下，我们将再次使用基于零的索引
because we like it.
因为我们喜欢它。
So starting at number i, what's the longest
所以从数字i开始，最长的是
increasing sub-sequence I can get?
我可以获得越来越多的子序列？
So the length of the blah, blah, blah.
等等，等等，等等。
The length of, you get the point.
的长度，你明白了。
OK so I'm going to have an array again, right?
好，所以我将再次拥有一个数组，对吗？
Which stores the answers.
哪个存储答案。
The array is going to be named dp.
该数组将被命名为dp。
If I have N numbers I'm going to have N elements, from 0
如果我有N个数字，我将有N个元素，从0开始
to N minus 1.
到N减1。
Suppose I'm at element i.
假设我在元素i处。
And suppose this original array is called a.
并假设此原始数组称为a。
I'm in the mood for good variable names today.
我今天想要好的变量名。
So how do I compute dp if i?
那么，如果我怎么计算dp？
Let's write some pseudocode for it.
让我们为其编写一些伪代码。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] N minus i--
观众：[听不清] N减i--
PROFESSOR: So what's h?
教授：那是什么？
AUDIENCE: The number of steps we want to take--
听众：我们要采取的步骤数量-
PROFESSOR: So if I'm going from 3 to 4 h would be what?
教授：那么，如果我从3到4个小时会是什么？
AUDIENCE: 2.
听众：2。
3.
3。
PROFESSOR: OK so I'm going to have
教授：好的，我要
to do additions and subtractions,
做加减法，
and this is going to confuse me.
这会让我感到困惑。
So how about I propose this.
那我建议这个。
What you say is perfectly valid, but instead, to make sure
您所说的完全正确，但要确保
I don't make too many mistakes, I'm
我不会犯太多错误，我是
going to look at the number I land at.
看看我的电话号码。
At the index directly.
直接在索引处。
So I'm going to say I start at i and end at j.
因此，我要说的是我从i开始，到j结束。
So the next step is j.
因此，下一步是j。
And then your h is j minus i.
然后您的h为j减去i。
So I'm not going to look at the number of numbers I hop over,
所以我不会看我跳过的数字数量，
all I care about is where do I land.
我唯一关心的是我在哪里着陆。
So what's the next number in the sub-sequence?
那么，子序列中的下一个数字是什么？
If I do it that way, where do I start?
如果我那样做，我应该从哪里开始？
AUDIENCE: i plus 1.
听众：我加1。
So I can choose the same number twice, right?
所以我可以选择两次相同的数字，对吗？
So plus 1 to n.
所以加1到n。
And then I'm going to have a choices array here that I
然后我将在这里有一个选择数组
start, initialize with nothing.
开始，什么都不初始化。
And then what's the candidate, if I'm at j?
如果我在j，那候选人是什么？
So what answer am I looking at?
那我在看什么答案？
AUDIENCE: dp of j.
听众：j的dp。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So if I'm at i, and I'm considering choosing j
因此，如果我在i，并且我正在考虑选择j
as the next element, then my sequence will be-- my sequence
作为下一个元素，那么我的顺序将是-我的顺序
length will be dp of j almost.
长度几乎是j的dp。
Plus 1.
加1。
OK, can I choose all the-- can I go through all the j's?
好的，我可以选择所有的-我可以遍历所有的j吗？
Can I go from 3 to 2.
我可以从3转到2。
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
The number at j is greater than--
j处的数字大于-
PROFESSOR: If the number at j is greater than the number at i
教授：如果j处的数字大于i处的数字
then I have this new choice, dp of j plus 1.
那么我有这个新选择，dp j加1。
What do I do with it?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Stick it in choices.
听众：坚持选择。
PROFESSOR: Stick it in choices.
教授：坚持选择。
Sorry this is append.
抱歉，这是附加内容。
And afterwards?
然后呢？
And by the way, this thing is under the if.
顺便说一句，这件事在if下。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK and I'm missing one choice this way.
教授：好的，我这样就错过了一个选择。
What's my default choice?
我的默认选择是什么？
So what's the sequence length if I just stay there?
那么，如果我呆在那里，序列长度是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So if I decide to not choose anything after 3
教授：所以，如果我决定3点后不选择任何东西
then I have a number, 1.
然后我有一个数字1。
Small detail, again one of those things
小细节，再次是这些事情之一
that costs you one point if you get it wrong.
如果您弄错了，那将花费您一分。
OK so I have a default.
确定，所以我有默认值。
So I know that this is going to be well-defined,
所以我知道这将是明确的，
and I have all my possible choices.
我有所有可能的选择。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: dp of j representing a [INAUDIBLE].
听众：j的dp代表[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So it's saying, if I'm at i,
教授：这就是说，如果我在我身边，
and the next number in the sequence
和序列中的下一个数字
is j, what's the longest sub-sequence-- the length
是j，最长的子序列是多少
of the longest sub-sequence starting at j?
开始于j的最长子序列？
So let's run the dp for this example actually.
因此，让我们实际运行此示例的dp。
Let's get a feel for why it works and how it works.
让我们来看看它为什么起作用以及如何起作用。
So I'm going to copy it again here.
所以我要在这里再次复制。
8, 3, 5, 2, 4, 9, 7, 11.
8、3、5、2、4、9、7、11
So this is a.
所以这是一个。
And dp is here.
dp在这里。
Where do I start by the way?
我从哪里开始？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So I have the algorithm here,
教授：所以我这里有算法，
how do I iterate?
我该如何迭代？
For i in--
因为我在-
AUDIENCE: N minus N is 0.
听众：N减去N为0。
PROFESSOR: N minus 1 all the way to 0.
教授：N减1一直到0。
So in this case we're going to start at 11, right?
所以在这种情况下，我们将从11开始，对吗？
The default choice is 1.
默认选择是1。
Do I have any other choice?
我还有其他选择吗？
Can I go forward?
我可以前进吗？
Nope.
不。
So this is going to be 1.
所以这将是1。
Now for 7 my array of choices has a default of 1.
现在，对于我的选择数组，默认值为1。
And then for-- let me write the indices too,
然后，让我也写索引，
so I don't get confused.
所以我不会感到困惑。
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
0、1、2、3、4、5、6、7
And these are i's.
这些是我的。
So we're at 7, i equals 6.
所以我们现在是7，等于6。
For j equals 7, is a of j greater than a of i?
对于j等于7，j的a是否大于i的a？
OK.
好。
So then 7, 11 is a possible choice, right?
那么7、11是一个可能的选择，对吗？
So if I choose 11 as the next point in my sequence,
因此，如果我选择11作为序列中的下一个点，
what's the total sequence length?
总序列长度是多少？
2.
2。
And 1 plus dp of 7 equals 2.
1加dp等于7。
So this is good.
所以这很好。
So far the answers add up.
到目前为止，答案加起来了。
So I have 1 and 2 as my candidates
所以我有1和2作为候选人
for the answer 2dp of 6.
对于6的答案2dp。
What's the maximum?
最高是多少？
All right.
好吧。
Works so far.
到目前为止工作。
How about 9?
9呢？
What are the possible answers for 9?
9的可能答案是什么？
So what's choices?
那有什么选择呢？
First there's 1, there's always 1.
首先是1，总是1。
And then for j equals 6, will the if be true?
然后，对于j等于6的if是否成立？
No.
没有。
I can't add a 7 after a 9, right?
我不能在9之后加上7，对吗？
So go to the next one.
因此，转到下一个。
For j equals 7, will the if be true?
如果j等于7，则if是否为真？
So this append will happen, right?
所以这个追加将会发生，对吗？
What will be appended in the array?
数组中将追加什么？
And this means that if I'm at 9, and then the next element is
这意味着如果我9岁，那么下一个元素是
11, the longest sequence I can get has length 2.
11，我可以获得的最长序列的长度为2。
OK, what's the answer for 9?
OK，9的答案是什么？
So if I start at 9 the longest sequence I can make
因此，如果我从9开始的最长序列
has length 2.
长度为2。
Let's look at 4 now.
现在让我们看4。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: What is?
教授：什么？
AUDIENCE: Just in general that's-- the problem is defined
听众：总的来说-问题已经定义
as, OK in this case you go from 9 to 11.
如，在这种情况下，您可以从9到11。
Or do you have to go from 9 to the next element?
还是必须从9转到下一个元素？
PROFESSOR: So this is the longest sub-sequence
教授：所以这是最长的子序列
if I do-- so the longest sub-sequence I get overall.
如果我愿意的话-我会得到最长的子序列。
I don't have to go to the next element.
我不必转到下一个元素。
So if my problem looks like this, what is the best answer?
因此，如果我的问题看起来像这样，最好的答案是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's almost defined as--
听众：它几乎被定义为-
PROFESSOR: So the problem is defined
教授：这样就定义了问题
as, this is your first element in the sub-sequence.
因为，这是子序列中的第一个元素。
What's the best answer you can get?
您能得到的最佳答案是什么？
AUDIENCE: I thought in that case it would be 1
听众：我当时认为是1
because there's nothing following it that's greater.
因为没有什么比这更大的了。
PROFESSOR: This is greater, right?
教授：更大，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Unless it skips.
听众：除非跳过。
PROFESSOR: So it's a sub-sequence, not a sub-string,
教授：这是一个子序列，而不是子字符串，
which means it can skip.
这意味着它可以跳过。
I hope I got these right.
我希望我没错。
So you can skip, otherwise the answer
所以你可以跳过，否则答案
would be a bit easier to compute.
计算起来会容易一些。
OK how about 4?
好4怎么样？
So let's start with 1 because that's the easy one.
因此，我们从1开始，因为这很简单。
And then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: 1, 3, 3, 2, right?
观众：1、3、3、2，对吧？
Because it's going to be 3 for that one.
因为那将是3。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: And then 3 for this one.
观众：然后是3。
PROFESSOR: 3 for this one.
教授：这个是3。
AUDIENCE: And then 2.
听众：然后2。
PROFESSOR: So all these are bigger, so all of them
教授：所有这些都更大，所以所有这些
are possible next candidates.
可能是下一个候选人。
And these are the sequence lengths
这些是序列长度
that I can get if I choose them.
如果选择它们，我可以得到。
Final answer?
最后的答案？
AUDIENCE: 3.
听众：3。
PROFESSOR: 3 maximum.
教授：最多3位。
AUDIENCE: But for setting the parent pointers
听众：但是要设置父指针
you'd want to take the closest thing, right?
你想拿最近的东西吧？
PROFESSOR: As long as it's a maximum I don't care.
教授：只要是最高限额，我不在乎。
So what are possible parent pointers here?
那么，这里可能有哪些父指针？
The 2's, right?
2的吧？
So either this or this.
所以这个或这个。
Do I care which one I chose?
我在乎选择哪一个吗？
AUDIENCE: No, I guess I don't.
听众：不，我想不是。
PROFESSOR: As long as I choose a 2.
教授：只要我选择2。
From a 3 I know I have to go to a 2.
从3开始，我知道我必须进入2。
I can't go to 1 because otherwise it
我不能去1，否则
wouldn't be as long as possible.
不会尽可能长。
And then from 2's I have to go to 1,
然后从2开始，我必须转到1
and I don't care which one.
我不在乎哪一个。
OK how about 2, what's dp of 2?
好吧，2的dp怎么样？
Does everyone else see it?
其他人看到了吗？
So these are all possible choices
这些都是可能的选择
because they're all bigger than 2.
因为它们都大于2。
And I get 1 if I don't choose anything, 4, 3, 3, 2.
如果我什么都没选择，我将得到1、4、3、3、2。
So 4 is the biggest answer.
所以4是最大的答案。
Let's look at this one, this one's a bit interesting, 5.
让我们来看看这个，这个有点有趣，5。
So what are the choices here?
那么，这里有哪些选择？
1 if I don't look at anything else.
1，如果我什么也没看。
Then?
然后？
There's a 3, 4, then 9.
分别是3、4、9。
A 3, 4, then 7.
A 3、4，然后是7。
And?
和？
And a 2 for the 11.
而11则为2。
So this if is going to skip these two elements, which
因此，如果要跳过这两个元素，
I can't use to make an increasing sub-sequence.
我不能用来增加子序列。
And then it's going to look at these ones,
然后要看这些
and it's going to add 1 to the numbers here.
并将这里的数字加1。
And I get 3.
我得到3。
OK.
好。
What is the answer for 3?
3的答案是什么？
AUDIENCE: 4.
听众：4。
PROFESSOR: And what is the answer for 8?
教授：那8的答案是什么？
AUDIENCE: 3.
听众：3。
PROFESSOR: Right, the choices are 9 and 11.
教授：对，选择是9和11。
Starting with itself and then 9 and 11.
从自身开始，然后从9和11开始。
So now what's the longest-- what's the answer overall
那么现在最长的是什么-总体答案是什么
for this problem?
对于这个问题？
So it's not dp of 0, right?
所以不是dp为0，对吧？
Before when I had blackjack I knew
在我有二十一点时，我知道
that I have to start at the first card.
我必须从第一张牌开始。
So the answer was dp of 0.
因此答案是dp为0。
In this case it's not dp 0, it's the maximum
在这种情况下，它不是dp 0，而是最大值
of all the dp's here.
所有dp都在这里。
Because I can start my sequence anywhere I want.
因为我可以在任何需要的地方开始序列。
So I have to take the maximum.
因此，我必须采取最大的努力。
And that's the overall answer, which in this case is 4.
这就是整体答案，在本例中为4。
OK does it make sense now?
好，现在有意义吗？
Somewhat?
有些？
So if you don't understand please look
所以如果你不明白，请看
at how you'd represent this as a graph.
您如何将其表示为图表。
The idea is that the numbers are nodes
这个想法是数字是节点
and you draw an edge between numbers,
然后在数字之间画一条边
where the first number is smaller than the second number.
其中第一个数字小于第二个数字。
Write that formulation, write the shortest path for that,
写那个公式，写最短的路径，
and see how that matches to this.
并查看如何与此匹配。